import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData: ExamData = {
  title: "Gas Turbines - Fuel Systems",
  questions: [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "Fuel is heated from which of the following?",
      "options": [
        "Air conditioning air",
        "Air from the compressor",
        "Air from the bootstrap",
        "Air from the turbine"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Fuel is heated to:",
      "options": [
        "prevent waxing.",
        "ensure vapour losses are minimized",
        "make it more viscous",
        "make it easier to flow under all conditions"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Fuel booster pumps are situated in:",
      "options": [
        "the fuel tanks",
        "the line between the main fuel tanks and the engine",
        "low pressure side of the engine",
        "high pressure side of the engine"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "In a fuel-cooled oil cooler the ……… is maintained ……… than the ………",
      "options": [
        "fuel pressure higher oil pressure",
        "oil pressure lower fuel",
        "fuel pressure same oil pressure",
        "oil pressure higher fuel pressure"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "In a high bypass engine fuel pumps are driven by:",
      "options": [
        "high pressure turbine",
        "high pressure compressor",
        "low pressure compressor",
        "intermediate compressor"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "The effect of the high pressure compressor outlet pressure exceeding its maximum value would be:",
      "options": [
        "pressure sensor input to fuel control unit (FCU), FCU reduce fuel, reduce rpm",
        "pressure sensor input to fuel control unit (FCU), FCU increase fuel, increase rpm",
        "pressure sensor input to fuel control unit (FCU), bleed valve open, bleed off excess volume of air",
        "pressure sensor input to fuel control unit (FCU), bleed valve open, bleed off excess pressure"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which of the following is a normal stopping device for a gas turbine?",
      "options": [
        "LP shut off valve close",
        "Fuel tank booster pumps select off",
        "HP shut off valve close",
        "Isolate electrics from engine"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct statement?",
      "options": [
        "When an engine is running, the combustion chamber drain is closed by a pressure operated NRV",
        "When an engine is running, the combustion chamber drains tank is opened by a pressure operated NRV",
        "When the engine is shut down the drains tank closes to minimize fuel losses",
        "When the engine is shut down, residual fuel is syphoned directly back to the fuel tanks to minimize fuel losses"
      ],
      "answer": 0
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "The fuel flowmeter is situated:",
      "options": [
        "between LP pump and the FCOC",
        "between LP pump and HP pump",
        "just after FCU",
        "between HP shut off valve and fuel nozzles"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "An overheat in the turbine will result in:",
      "options": [
        "an electrical signal from the thermocouple sent directly to the FCU and fuel being reduced",
        "an electrical signal from the thermocouple amplified then sent directly to the FCU and fuel flow being reduced",
        "pilot observing overheat on temperature gauge then subsequently throttling back the engine, therefore reducing fuel",
        "pilot observing overheat on temperature gauge then subsequently increasing rpm to increase airflow, to increase cooling air, to decrease turbine temperature"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "Aircraft flying at FL420. If the booster pumps feeding the engine cease to work:",
      "options": [
        "the engine would close down immediately",
        "the LP pump will draw fuel from the tank, but there may be a possibility of cavitation due to the low pressure and low boiling point of the fuel",
        "the LP pump will draw fuel from the tank, but there may be a possibility of cavitation due to the low pressure and higher boiling point of the fuel",
        "the LP pump will draw fuel from the tank, but there may be a possibility of cavitation due to the higher pressure and higher boiling point of the fuel"
      ],
      "answer": 1
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "The fuel-cooled oil cooler:",
      "options": [
        "heats the oil and cools the fuel",
        "heats the fuel only",
        "cools the oil only",
        "heats the fuel and cools the oil"
      ],
      "answer": 3
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "On a cold day, the idle speed of a gas turbine engine which has no fuel control unit compensation:",
      "options": [
        "is unaffected by temperature",
        "will increase",
        "will decrease",
        "will increase by no more than 4%"
      ],
      "answer": 2
    }
  ]
};